COLLINS OMONDI OJWANG

omondicollins163@gmail.com github.com/Ojwang-crypto linkedin.com/in/collins-omondi-45a8b81bb/+254740443536

Professional Summary

Experienced software engineer with a passion for creating innovative systems that improve company efficiency and effectiveness, ability to understand and test software, working knowledge of software development and a strong understanding of core internet technologies. Well-versed in technology and coding to design dependable and user-friendly systems

Skills

→ Programming Languages: PHP, Python, JavaScript, C/C++

→ Data-Interchange Format: JSON

→ SQL Database Systems: MySQL, PostgreSQL

→ Markup Languages: XML, HTML5

→ Style Sheet Language: CSS

→ Source Control Tools: Git, Github

→ Web Scraping in Python

Software Architectural Pattern: MVC

Frameworks: Laravel, Django, Bootstrap

Web Servers: Apache HTTPD

API testing tool: Postman API Automation tool: Selenium

Cloud Technologies: GCP, AWS

Work History

Software Development Engineer In Test Safaricom PLC (Jan 2022 - Present)

- Part of the quality assurance team tasked with the setting up of MPESA from scratch in Ethiopia through testing of various Mpesa products in order to meet quality.
- Created detailed, comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases
- Report bugs and errors and Track in Application Lifecycle Management in a timely manner
- Collaborate with QA Engineers to develop effective strategies and test plans
- Did Exploratory tests and system test
- Created accurate and efficient test scripts for automated testing of certain products and features using Selenium web driver and Python
- Work closely with the scrum team to ensure the process of building software promotes quality
- Familiarity with Agile software development methodologies
- Involved in Scrum practices, Daily Stand-Ups, Sprint Planning, Story Point estimation, sprint review

IT Support Specialist (Attachment) Kenya Power and Lighting Company (Sept 2021 - Dec 2021)

- Manage IT, Network Racks and Cabinet including network switches, routers, patch panels and cables.
- Maintaining computer equipment, installing new software updates, repairing damaged hardware
- Doing preventive maintenance of equipment and assets in order to keep them running and prevent any costly unplanned downtime from unexpected equipment failure.
- Repairing computers and other technology including upgrading of software or hardware systems
- Troubleshooting any software issues that may arise and providing user support
- Configuring laptops, printers, scanners and email accounts.

Web Development Discover JKUAT

- ➤ Wrote well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices
- ➤ Gathered and refined specifications and requirements based on technical needs
- ➤ Integrated data from various back-end services and databases
- ➤ Had an in-depth understanding of connecting front-end with back-end
- > Stayed plugged into emerging technologies/industry trends and applying them into operations and activities
- ➤ Created website layout using standard HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap to develop seamless web experience.
- > Cooperated with other web designers to match visual design intent

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bsc Business Information Technology Second Class Upper 2018 - 2022.

Projects

- Developed an ecommerce system for an online shop. <u>link here</u>
- Developed a complete personal blog website link here
- Developed, Integrated back-end services and database for camp website <u>link here</u>
- Food ordering system

• Video chat application <u>link here</u>

Certifications

• Scrum Fundamentals Certified

• Cisco module 1

• Certificate in web design

• Agile Testing

Test Automation Foundation API Testing Foundation Behavior Driven Development

REFEREES

1. Mr. Sammy Mwaura Kimama

ICT Technician.

KPLC

Tel: +254721438949

2. Mr. Nobert Okoth

Software Test Engineer

Safaricom PLC

Email: nobertokoth18@gmail.com

Tel: +254758551314

3. Mr. Walter Ochieng

Software Test Lead

Safaricom PLC

Tel: +254705994560

walterochieng6950@gmail.com